(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
絆チェックで魔力を集めて告知しろ！
Gather magical power with a bond check and make an announcement!
は、は、は、は、は、は、は、は！
Ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha!
皆さん！こんやっぴー！ホロライブ4期生の常闇トワ様です！イェーイ！
Everyone! Kon-yappi! It's Hololive 4th gen's Tokoyami Towa-sama! Yay!
もうとんでもないテンションで入ってきたんですけど。
I just came in with such crazy high energy.
まあ、はい、ちょっと、ちょっと今、直前までね、
Well, yes, until just now,
今日来てくれるみんなと大笑いしてたんで、
I was laughing my head off with everyone who's here today,
ありえないテンションで入ってきちゃいました。すみません。
so I came in with impossible levels of energy. Sorry.
先に謝っておきますけども。
I'll apologize for it in advance.
はい、めっちゃ笑ってるやん、おい。
Wow, you're laughing so much.
で、はい。今日はなんと、みんなに重大発表があります！イェーイ！
And, yes. Today, I actually have a major announcement for everyone! Yay!
でもね、その重大発表には、なんと魔力を集めて、
But you see, for that major announcement, I actually have to gather magical power,
トワが真の力を解放しなきゃいけないんです。
and Towa has to release her true strength.
え、トワ、色やば。ごめん。
Oh, Towa's color looks weird. Sorry.
え、そういうことになっているんですね。はい。
Well, anyway, that's how it's going to be. Yes.
ねえ、ちょ、みんなの声聞こえてんの？
Hey, can you guys hear them?
すごいんだけど、あっちも大笑いが。
It's crazy, they're laughing so much over there too.
え、そういうことになってるんです。はい。
Yeah, that's what's happening. Yes.
ハッシュタグ、トワ様重大発表でね、
I'd be happy if you all tweeted a lot with the hashtag
みんなっぱい呟いてくれたら嬉しいなと思います。
#TowaSamaMajorAnnouncement.
応援してね！
Please support me!
そして、まあ、もう何回も話に出ちゃってるんですけど、
And, well, I've already mentioned it a few times, but...
今日はゲストがいるので、そちらのゲストと一緒に協力して
We have guests today, so I'm going to work together with them
魔力を集めていこうかなって思います。
to gather magical power.
だってお釈迦様、あ、悪魔だから。え、ということで。
Because I'm a buddha... I mean, a devil. So, anyway.
早速呼んじゃいましょう。みんなー！
Let's call them out right away. Everyone!
何笑ってんねん！
Why are you laughing?!
はい！ぺこちゃんが死にそうで...
Yes! Peko-chan is about to die...
死ぬな、ぺこちゃん。ぺこちゃんが...
Don't die, Peko-chan. Peko-chan is...
しんどい...
It's tough...
どうしたぺこら？
What's wrong Pekora?
いや、違う。あの、さっきまで配信のさ、
No, it's just, before the stream started,
時に前にさ、笑ったネタを引きずらないように
we said we'd try hard not to let the stuff
頑張ろうねって言ってたのに、
we were laughing about drag on, but...
トワ様やらかしちゃってるからさ。
Towa-sama went and messed up.
ぺこちゃんそれ過敏だよ。もう、大丈夫、全部じゃん。
Peko-chan, you're too sensitive. It's fine, it's everything.
ぺこちゃん、ぺこちゃん結構後から笑い来るタイプで。
Peko-chan is the type where the laughter comes late.
そうだよ。
That's right.
みんなが一息ついた時に一人でケラケラ笑ってた。
She was laughing by herself after everyone else had settled down.
そうだったね。うん。
That's how it was. Yeah.
はい！ということで。じゃあ自己紹介していきたいと思います。
Alright! So. Let's do some self-introductions.
ミオちゃんからどうぞ。
Starting with Mio-chan.
はい！うち、うち、うちだよ！
Yes! It's me, me, it's me!
大神ミオだよ！
I'm Ookami Mio!
ホロライブゲーマーズの大神ミオです！
Hololive Gamers' Ookami Mio!
お次！ちわーす！
Next! Hello!
ホロライブ2期生！大空スバルです！
Hololive 2nd gen! Oozora Subaru!
よろしくお願いします！
Nice to meet you!
おい！おい！ごめんやん。
Hey! Hey! Sorry about that.
次、ぼたんちゃん！
Next, Botan-chan!
はい、ホロライブ5期生、ららいおん、獅白ぼたんです。
Yes, Hololive 5th gen, La-Lion, Shishiro Botan.
よろしくお願いします。
Nice to meet you.
はい次！
Alright next!
はい！こんぺここんぺここんぺこー！
Yes! Kon-peko kon-peko kon-peko!
ホロライブ3期生の、兎田ぺこらぺこー！
Hololive 3rd gen's Usada Pekora-peko!
どーも、どーも！
Hello, hello!
はい！ということで、今日このメンバーでやるのは！
Alright! So, what we're doing today with this group is!
心合わせて魔力を集める「団結ボックス」！
Gathering magical power with our hearts in sync: "Unity Box"!
あーやばいやばいやばい！
Ah, oh no, oh no, oh no!
おかえりー！
Welcome back!
速い速い！
Fast, fast!
あーなんかだけ…痛い痛い痛い！
Ah, it's just... ow ow ow!
アップだからいいけど、引きで見ると中々…
It's fine because it's a close-up, but from a distance, it's quite...
引きで見るとみんな結構…進…進めてるね。
From a distance, everyone's really... moving... moving along.
うるさいわね！見なさい、見なさいこれ。
Shut up! Look, look at this.
うるさいわね、こちら見て。
Shut up, look over here.
何？何これ？箱ジャンケン？
What? What's this? Box rock-paper-scissors?
これはね、あの…この箱には魔力を集めている恐ろしい猫が封じ込められている。
This is, you see... inside this box, a terrifying cat that collects magic power is sealed away.
猫？何、猫？
A cat? What, a cat?
猫なんている？いないよ。
Are there cats? There aren't any.
そうだ、今日猫いないじゃん。
That's right, there are no cats today.
さあ、まあこうやってね、あの、箱を擦り擦りすると…
Now, if I rub the box like this...
擦り擦り？擦り擦り？
Rubbing? Rubbing?
何？擦り擦り？
What? Rubbing?
うわ！何何？
Whoa! What, what?
僕がこの団結ボックスの、猫だにゃ～。
I'm the cat of this Unity Box-nya.
燻製？燻製じゃん。
Smoked? It's smoked.
団結BOXの猫？
Cat of the Unity Box?
この箱から出すお題に合わせて、みんなの心が合っていることを証明できたら…
If you can prove that your hearts are in sync with the prompts I give from this box...
僕の魔力をトワに分けてあげてもいいよ～。
...I might share some of my magic power with Towa.
ええ、マジに？魔力！
Wait, really? Magic power!
まずは手始めに…
First, for starters...
「猫又おかゆ」っぽいポーズを全員で揃えてみてね～。
...everyone try to match a 'Nekomata Okayu-like' pose together.
ばにゃ～。
Ba-nya!
何だこれ？
What's this?
え～、ということでこの猫が説明してくれたように…
Well, as this cat explained...
トワたちの心は一つにしてお題に答えていけば、魔力がもらえてトワは重大発表ができるんだよ！アンダースタン？
If we make our hearts one and answer the prompts, we'll get magic power and I can make a major announcement! Understand?
よく分かんないけど、まずはおかゆ先輩っぽいポーズを全員で揃えればいいってことぺこですな。
I don't really get it, but basically we just need to match Okayu-senpai's pose together, peko.
なんか今いち乗り…乗り切れてないんだけど。
I'm not quite feeling it yet.
そうみたいだね。
Seems so.
すごいな、さすがぺこらちゃん！じゃ、みんな仕切りの中に入ってね！
Amazing, as expected of Pekora-chan! Now, everyone get inside the partitions!
はい、入りましたか？
Okay, are you in?
入ったよー！
We're in!
ということでここからはお互いが見えない状態で、猫からのお題に答えていきます。
So from here, we'll answer the cat's prompts while unable to see each other.
あくまで猫呼びなんだね。
You're sticking to calling her a cat.
猫又おかゆじゃなくて、猫っていう別の存在なんだね。
So it's not Nekomata Okayu, but a different being called 'cat'.
湯気猫ね、湯気猫から。
Steam-cat, from the steam-cat.
え～、そうしましたら最初のお題は「猫又おかゆっぽいポーズを全員一致させろ」です！
Well then, the first prompt is "Everyone match a Nekomata Okayu-like pose"!
お題 猫又おかゆっぽいポーズを全員一致
Prompt: Everyone match a Nekomata Okayu-like pose
それでは団結ボックススタート！
Now, Unity Box start!
え、もうこれ行っちゃっていいの？
Wait, can we just go?
え、じゃあ決めた？みんな、決めたかな？
Wait, decided? Everyone, have you decided?
これしかないと思う。
I think it can only be this.
え、これマジで一緒じゃないといけないってことだよ。
This means we really have to be the same.
行くよ、いい？もういいのね？行くよ！3、2、1、ポーズ！
Here we go, ready? Ready now? Go! 3, 2, 1, pose!
え、あれ？どうなんだ？
Eh, wait? How is it?
どう？どうだ？
How? How is it?
あれ？ミオちゃんしゃがんでね？
Wait? Mio-chan, aren't you squatting?
ミオちゃんだけしゃがんでね？他、一緒じゃない？
Only Mio-chan is squatting? Aren't the others the same?
他、一緒っぽくない？一緒だ！ミオちゃん！
Aren't the others the same? They are! Mio-chan!
あれ？待って！今の失敗？それは
Wait! Was that a fail?
いやいやいや、これは猫又おかゆのビジュアルだよね、たしか。
No no no, this is Nekomata Okayu's visual, surely.
あるある！おめでとうございます！ってこうだったよね？
It exists! It was like this for "Congratulations", right?
座ってもあったし、ポーズじゃない？
There was a sitting one too, isn't it a pose?
おうちで見たもん！
I saw it at home!
いない、あれはおかゆ。金曜ロードショーとかでなんか見そうな感じ。
That's not Okayu. It looks like something you'd see on Friday Road Show.
なんかちょっと、某、ね。トトロ的なやつ。
Like some kind of... Totoro-like thing.
これは…失敗！
This is... a fail!
ごめんトワ～、魔力、魔力～。
Sorry Towa, magic power, magic power.
そうだよ、トワ悪魔になりたいんだから。
That's right, since Towa wants to become a demon.
もう悪魔なんですけど！子悪魔だから！大悪魔になりてんだな。
I'm already a demon! Just a small one! I want to become a great demon.
じゃあそうしましたら仕切りをボーンと！
Then, the partitions go boom!
開けて、次のお題はこちら、パン！
Open, and the next prompt is this, bam!
お題 常闇トワといえば？で思いつくポーズを全員バラバラ
Prompt: When you think of Tokoyami Towa? Match a pose, but all different
「常闇トワといえば？」で思いつくポーズを全員バラバラだって！
"When you think of Tokoyami Towa?" Match a pose, and everyone must be different!
え、もうこれ今日のトワだったらあれになっちゃうけど。
Eh, but if it's today's Towa, it'll be that one.
あれだよね？それトワがやるから、それトワがやるから。
It's that one, right? Since Towa will do that, Towa will do it.
今日のトワで、今日のトワで…
With today's Towa, today's Towa...
バラバラにしなきゃいけないんだよね。分かった、バラバラだよ。
We have to be different, right. Got it, different.
バラバラにしなきゃいけない。そうだね。トワっぽいポーズ、全員バラバラだ。
We have to be different. Right. Towa-like poses, all different.
そうだ。え、全員バラバラ？どうしよう。
Right. Eh, all different? What should I do?
じゃあトワはあれやるから、みんなはトワのやつやらないで。
Then I'll do "that", so everyone don't do mine.
えー！マジで？待って、決まってない！
Eh! Seriously? Wait, it's not decided!
決まってないぞ！トワっぽいポーズたくさんあるでしょ？捨てるよ！何でもいいから！
It's not decided! There are lots of Towa-like poses, right? I'll throw one out! Anything's fine!
ね、確かに、いろんなポーズしているかもしれない。
Yeah, certainly, she might be doing various poses.
じゃあさ、でもいろんなポーズしているってことはさ、当たり範囲が広いってことだよ。
Well then, but the fact she does various poses means the "hit range" is wide.
じゃあいいですか？行きますよ！では、常闇トワっぽいポーズバラバラまで…
Are you ready? Here we go! Now, Tokoyami Towa-like poses, different...
3、2、1、ポン！
3, 2, 1, pon!
お！あれ？どう？お！え、バラバラじゃん？
Oh! Wait? How is it? Oh! Eh, aren't they all different?
バラバラじゃん！これ正解じゃない？これは正解！
They're all different! Isn't this correct? This is correct!
やったー！おめでとうー！
Yay! Congratulations!
お題：常闇トワといえば？で思いつくポーズを / 全員バラバラ
Prompt: A pose that comes to mind for 'Tokoyami Towa' / Everyone different
嘘でしょ！
No way!
とわっぽいかどうかが怪しいけど...
Whether it's Towa-like or not is suspicious, but...
確かにさ、言っとくけど一番とわっぽくないぜ！
True, let me tell you, that was the least Towa-like!
そうだそうだ！一番とわっぽくない！
Yeah, yeah! The least Towa-like!
なにこれ、なにこれ？
What's this, what's this?
なにこれ？ロボットでしょ？
What's this? A robot, right?
さっきロボットの真似してたから...
Because you were imitating a robot earlier...
さっきずっとロボットのポーズしてたわ。
You were doing robot poses the whole time.
でもこれは、可愛かったし！可愛かったし！
But this was cute! It was cute!
とりあえずチャレンジ成功！
Anyway, challenge successful!
イエーイ！
Yay!
ゆるい感じでいいけど！
I like the relaxed vibe though!
でもさ、楽しければよくない？
But hey, isn't it fine as long as it's fun?
そうだよね、そうだよ！
That's right, yeah!
お題：水着でするポーズといえば？で思いつくポーズを / 全員バラバラ
Prompt: A pose that comes to mind for a swimsuit? / Everyone different
ということで次のお題はこちら、ポン！
So the next theme is this, pon!
水着でするポーズと言えば？
Speaking of poses in a swimsuit?
で思いつくポーズを全員バラバラ！
Everyone do a different pose that comes to mind!
これはホロライブサマーがあるからいけるだろ！
We can do this since we have Hololive Summer!
いけるいける！バラバラだよ、バラバラ！
We can do it! Different, different!
水着でしょ？
Swimsuit, right?
でもみんなさ、撮ったじゃん、水着で写真。
But everyone, we took photos in swimsuits.
これさ全員一緒のポーズだったらやばいからさ...
It'll be bad if we all do the same pose...
全員バラバラの自分のポーズすれば...
So if we each do a different pose of our own...
確かに！被んないんじゃね？
True! We won't overlap, right?
ぺこらも被んないように、そうだこれだったな。
Pekora, I'll make sure not to overlap, right, it was this.
よし、じゃあ行きますよ。水着でするポーズ、全員バラバラまで...
Alright, here we go. Poses in a swimsuit, everyone being different...
３、２、１、ポン！
3, 2, 1, Pon!
え、どう？どう？
Eh, how is it? How is it?
え、なんかみおちゃんと被ってない？
Eh, isn't it overlapping with Mio-chan?
あれ、角度が違う？
Wait, is the angle different?
被ってるように見える...
It looks like they overlap...
被ってない、私は手の前なの！
They don't overlap, mine are in front!
ぼたんは手を前で、みおちゃんは...
Botan's hands are in front, and Mio-chan...
私は手は上です！
My hands are up!
ぺこらちゃんはハート！
Pekora-chan is a heart!
スバルちゃんは元気で、とわはこういう感じで...
Subaru-chan is energetic, and Towa is like this...
え、これクリアじゃない？
Wait, isn't this a clear?
イエーイ！成功！
Yay! Success!
全員バラバラいいわ！
Everyone different is great!
やばい、ちょっとやっちゃったかな...
Oh no, maybe I overdid it...
でも次はわかんないからね。
But you never know about the next one.
やっちゃっていいんだよ！
It's okay to do it!
いいの？こんな簡単で。
Is it okay for it to be this easy?
いいわけないじゃん、重大発表させたくねーよ！
Of course not, I don't want to let you make the major announcement!
お題：アイドルポーズといえば？で思いつくポーズを / 全員一致
Prompt: A pose that comes to mind for an idol? / Everyone matching
ということで、次。次のお題はこちら、ポン！
So, next. The next theme is this, pon!
アイドルポーズと言えば？
Speaking of idol poses?
で思いつくポーズを全員一致！
Everyone must match the pose that comes to mind!
これはちょっと話し合う必要あるな。全員一致か。
We need to discuss this a bit. Everyone matching, huh.
どのアイドル像に寄せるか。
Which idol image should we go with?
どのアイドルポーズ？
Which idol pose?
誰にする？分かりやすい人にしようよ。
Who should it be? Let's pick someone obvious.
そら先輩とか！
Like Sora-senpai!
えー、そら先輩だったら多分あれしかないと思うな。
Eh, if it's Sora-senpai, I think there's only one.
あれって何？
What is 'that'?
でもこれさ、ミスったら結構大ダメージ負いそうじゃない？
But if we mess this up, won't it be a huge blow?
大空スバルにしようよ！
Let's go with Oozora Subaru!
大空スバルもわかんないよ！
We don't know Oozora Subaru either!
大空スバルはもう公式のページあるじゃん！
Oozora Subaru has an official page already!
え、待って、どれだ？
Eh, wait, which one?
絶妙なやつがなんかあった気がする。
I feel like there was an exquisite one.
やっぱり船長、船長じゃない？
After all, isn't it Sencho (Marine)? Sencho!
マリンかぺこちゃんかな？
Marine or Peko-chan?
ぺこちゃんも分かりやすい気がする。
I feel like Peko-chan is obvious too.
ぺこちゃん、いつもあのポーズしてるなってあるある。
Peko-chan, there's that common one she always does.
ぺこちゃんにしよ！
Let's do Peko-chan!
ぺこらわかんないんだけど！
Pekora doesn't know!
やってるやってる！ぺこちゃんにしよ！
You do, you do! Let's do Peko-chan!
アイドルと言えばで思いつくポーズ、全員一致で揃えろ！
Idol poses, match them all together!
せーの、ポン！
Ready, set, pon!
あれ？
Eh?
みんな合ってます？
Is everyone matching?
これですよ！アイドルと言ったらこぺこですよね？
This is it! When you say idol, it's this Peko, right?
私はぺこちゃんの立ち絵のアイドルポーズ。
I did Peko-chan's standing pose idol pose.
全員合ってねーじゃねーかよ！
They don't match at all!
え、これ？
Wait, this?
あ、そうだったっけ？
Ah, was that it?
でも、トワ様これハート作ってないけどね、いつも。
But Towa-sama doesn't usually make a heart like this.
サマーじゃん！サマー！サマーじゃん！お題サマーじゃん！
It's 'Summer'! Summer! It's 'Summer'! The prompt was 'Summer'!
ああ、サマーか。なるほどね。
Ah, 'Summer'. I see.
はい。ということで、え、じゃあ次どうぞ。ポン！
Okay. So, then, next one please. Bam!
何だ何だ？
What is it, what is it?
猫又おかゆからのお題。
A prompt from Nekomata Okayu.
「猫又おかゆがメスを注入してる時のポーズを全員一致」
“All match the pose when Nekomata Okayu is injecting 'Mesu'”
「猫又おかゆがメスを注入してる時のポーズを全員一致」...えぐいことなん？
“All match the pose when Nekomata Okayu is injecting 'Mesu'”... Is that something nasty?
え、これおかゆさんのお題なんですけど。
Wait, this is Okayu-san's prompt.
他人にメスを注入してる時ってこと？
You mean when she's injecting 'Mesu' into someone else?
それとも自分に？自分に？！自分に？！
Or into herself? Herself?! Herself?!
マジで？！くさっ！え、どういうこと、どういうこと？
Seriously?! That's gross! Wait, what do you mean, what do you mean?
自分にどう注入するの？
How would she inject it into herself?
メスを注入...そのポーズってこと？
Injecting 'Mesu'... that pose?
分かんない、こうやってる時じゃない？え？！
I don't know, maybe like this? What?!
ケツに？！
In the butt?!
どういう解釈をすればいいんだよ、これは！
How am I supposed to interpret this?!
でも今のは、自分、スバルちゃんのみんな見ちゃったから。
But since I just saw everyone's, including Subaru-chan's...
見ちゃった。両手でこう、こう...。
I saw it. Like this with both hands...
他人のじゃん、他人の。
That's for someone else, someone else.
こうやって、頭に。
Like this, in the head.
頭に...やばいだろ！
In the head... that's crazy!
他人じゃん、他人。人にか！
It's someone else, someone else. Into a person?!
え、なんか襲いかかってるみたいにならない？
Wait, doesn't it look like she's attacking someone?
え、他人、他人に...。
Wait, someone else, someone else...
え、じゃあ他人にメスを入れてるってどうしよう。
Wait, then what should we do for 'injecting Mesu into someone else'?
自分にじゃないの？これ。
Isn't it into herself? This.
え、自分になの？
Wait, into herself?
自分になの？やっぱりね、メス、自分にメスを入れるんだ。
Into herself? As I thought, she injects 'Mesu' into herself.
メスになりたいからさ。
Because she wants to be 'Mesu' (feminine).
え、なんかやばいポーズ取れそうで怖いんだけど。
Wait, I'm scared we might strike a really bad pose.
正解わかんねえ！
I don't know the right answer!
じゃあもうとりあえず、そこはもう甘えてやるか。
Well, for now, let's just go with our own interpretations.
え、でもさ、直接的にこれ...
Wait, but if we do this directly...
やばいよね、やばいよね。
It's bad, right? It's bad.
やばいよ、やばい。やばい、モザイクかけてくれ。
It's bad, bad. Bad, someone put a mosaic over this.
やばい、やばい、襲いかかってこないで！モザイクかけてくれ、もう。
Bad, bad, don't attack me! Put a mosaic over it already!
どうすればいいの？！難しすぎるよ、これ。
What should I do?! This is way too hard.
え、もういい、もういい。もういいかなって思ってる。
Wait, I've had enough. I think I'm done.
もういっか、もういいよね。
Whatever, it's fine now, right?
え、じゃあ、もう行くよこれ。なんかこれね、深掘りするととんでもないことになるから。
Okay, let's just go with this. If we dig into it, things will get crazy.
もう早くやろ。確かに。
Let's just do it quickly. True.
え、ということで。猫又おかゆがメスを注入してる時のポーズを全員一致！せーの！
So, here we go. Everyone match Okayu's 'Mesu injection' pose! Ready, set...
もう、こう、こうしかない！
This, this is all I've got!
こういう感じじゃない、もう。え、どう？
Isn't it like this? Well, how's it?
お！え、ぺこらちゃんは中腰でしょ？
Oh! Wait, Pekora-chan is in a half-crouch?
うん。
Yeah.
ミオちゃんは、え、それ注入されてるポーズじゃなくて？
Mio-chan, wait, isn't that a 'being injected' pose?
されてる側、にゃお〜。ああ、なるほどね。
The one being injected, nyao~. Ah, I see.
え、でもスバルちゃんは？ちょっとケツ、ケツ出しな感じか。
Wait, what about Subaru-chan? Kinda sticking your butt out.
あ、そう。や、でもおかゆ先輩ちょっと座ってるのが、あるかなみたいなイメージ。
Ah, right. No, but I have this image of Okayu-senpai sitting down.
あ、今、確かに。や、座りだね。感じながらよ。注射のポーズはしたけど。
Ah, now that you mention it. Yeah, it's a sitting pose. While feeling it. I did an injection pose though.
じゃあ私もさ、さっきこれだったからやばいなと思って。
Me too, I was doing this earlier and thought it was too much.
やばいやばいやばいって。ということで、おかゆからのお題は、失敗！
Bad, bad, bad! So, Okayu's prompt is... Failure!
ということで全然合わないじゃん。
See, we didn't match at all.
これ合わないとさ、ダメなのよ。わかる？
If we don't match, it's no good. You get it?
そんなこと言われてもお題難しいよ！
Don't say that, the prompt was too hard!
すぎるよ！ギリギリに立ってるよ、俺ら。
Way too hard! We're standing right on the edge!
いろんな意味で危ないよね。危ない、危ないからこうやって。
It's dangerous in many ways. It's dangerous, so we're doing this.
大丈夫、ライン踏んでも超えなきゃ大丈夫だから。
It's okay, as long as we step on the line but don't cross it, we're fine.
踏むなよ。人によってはアウトになるぞ。
Don't step on it. Depending on the person, it'll be 'Out'!
そうだぞ！はい、ということで仕切り直しましょう。カンニングはしちゃダメだからね。
That's right! Okay, so let's reset. No peeking allowed.
はい！はい！え、じゃあ次のお題どうぞ。ポン！
Yes! Yes! Okay, next prompt please. Bam!
え、「お化け屋敷でびっくりした常闇トワのポーズを全員一致」...おかゆから！
“All match Tokoyami Towa's pose when surprised in a haunted house”... From Okayu!
「お化け屋敷でびっくりした常闇トワのポーズを全員一致」
“All match Tokoyami Towa's pose when surprised in a haunted house”
え、じゃあトワが正解ってことぺこね。そうだね、トワが正解。
Wait, so Towa is the 'correct answer', peko. That's right, Towa is the answer.
そうだね。え、びっくりした時のポーズでしょ？もう決まりでしょ、こんなん。
Yeah. A surprised pose, right? It's already decided, obviously.
え、ぺこら、トワ様のこれかなっていうのがあるけどな。
Wait, I have an idea of what Towa-sama's pose might be.
パ、パ、パ、パ。私も、あるわ。
Pa-pa-pa-pa. I have one too.
え、ないな。まあ出たとこ勝負でやるか。じゃあ出たとこ勝負。オッケー。
I don't. Well, let's just go for it and see. Okay, let's wing it.
はい。じゃあ行きますよ。お化け屋敷でびっくりしたトワのポーズを全員一致で！せーの！
Okay. Here we go. Everyone match Towa's haunted house surprise pose! Ready, set...
あ！
Ah!
あれ？
Huh?
え、どう？ん？待って待って。え、ぺこちゃん可愛い。
Well, how is it? Huh? Wait, wait. Pekora-chan is cute.
え、なんかびっくりしてる...まあ、びっくりしたら見ないから。
Wait, like being surprised... well, if you're surprised, you don't look.
見ないの？なるほどな。え、トワはもうこれ、ほら、これ正解だからこれ。
You don't? I see. Look, Towa's is this! This is the correct one!
あ、可愛すぎないか？
Ah, isn't that too cute?
スバルちゃんのそれさ、狙ってるだろ、ウケを！
Subaru-chan, you're aiming for a laugh with that, aren't you?!
違うよ！これは、とんでもないことが起こった時に...
No! This is for when something absolutely crazy happens...
テンパりすぎて、一周回ってたか、よくわからない、よくわからない。
And you panic so much that you spin around or something, I don't even know.
それはイカれたタカのポーズだろ！
That's a 'crazy hawk' pose!
いや違う、こうなってないだろ！
No, it's not like that!
でもさ、待って、ミオちゃんも相当やばかったよ。
But wait, Mio-chan's was also pretty bad.
え、似たような...一緒だよね？
Wait, similar... they're the same, right?
いやいやいや、もうなんかそれはさ、違う。もっと可愛い感じだよ、トワは。
No, no, no, that's wrong. Towa is supposed to be more cute.
はぁ？！こっちだろ！こっちだよ、ミオの方が可愛い！
Hah?! It's this one! It's this one, Mio's is cuter!
何で正解がさ、怒られなきゃいけないんだよ！
Why do I, the one with the correct answer, have to be yelled at?!
おかゆ、トワには厳しいな。
Okayu is strict with Towa.
みんな全然わかってないよ。またまた失敗！
Everyone has no idea. Another failure!
ダメか。ダメだ。頼むわ、マジで。
No good, huh. It's no good. Come on, seriously.
はい。頼むわ、マジで。告知したいわ。
Okay. Seriously, please. I want to make the announcement.
告知したい。はい、では次ポン！
I want to announce it. Okay, next one! Bam!
お！「夏と聞いて思い浮かぶものを全員一致」
Oh! “All match what comes to mind when you hear 'Summer'”
「夏と聞いて思い浮かぶものを全員一致」
“All match what comes to mind when you hear 'Summer'”
上にお、何何？
What, what?
はい！次！ドーン！
Yes! Next! Boom!
お題：夏と聞いて思い浮かぶものを全員一致
Topic: Something you think of when you hear 'summer' - All in agreement
これは、後ろを見てください！ドーン！
For this one, please look behind you! Boom!
おー！
Oh!
あるぞ！
There's something there!
なんか色々ある！
There are a lot of things!
なるほど！
I see!
めっちゃあるよ！
There are so many!
ちょっと、水...
Wait, a lot of water...
いっぱいある！
There's plenty!
スイカ、浮き輪...
Watermelon, inner tube...
本当だ。
There really are.
おー。
Oh~
かき氷とかもあるじゃない。
There's also shaved ice.
かき氷と...
Shaved ice and...
スイカだ！
It's watermelon!
アイス、浮き輪...
Ice cream, inner tube...
5種類かな？
Are there 5 types?
おー。
Oh~
この中で、夏といえば思い...夏と言ったら思いつく、は？
In this, something you think of when you say... when you say 'summer' is... huh?
夏と言えば！
Speaking of summer!
切んなって！
Don't cut it off!
滑舌早すぎんだって！
You're speaking way too fast!
思い浮かぶものを...
Something you think of...
夏と聞いて思い浮かぶものを、活舌全員一致！
Something you think of when you hear 'summer', clearly, all in agreement!
夏と言えば、これだよね。
Speaking of summer, it has to be this.
これ、一瞬で決まった。夏っしょ？
This was decided in a second. It's summer, right?
夏。
Summer.
いや、これしかないでしょ。
No, this is the only one.
これしかない。
This is it.
これだ。
This one.
どれかなー。
Which one...
あ、決めた。
Oh, I've decided.
自分が思い描いていいよね？いいよ。
It's okay to pick what I think of, right? Yeah.
全員一致だよ。
All in agreement, okay?
はい。
Yes.
じゃ、せーので後ろ振り返って見せよう、みんなで。行くよ。
Then, on the count of three, let's all turn around and show it. Here we go.
せーの！これ！
Ready... This!
あー！
Ah!
あれ、これ多くない？
Wait, aren't there a lot of these?
え？
Eh?
あれ、スイカ。
Wait, watermelon.
あれ？
Huh?
スイカ！
Watermelon!
あれ、かき氷。
Wait, shaved ice.
浮き輪。
Inner tube.
なんかお祭りじゃない？あれ、かき氷は。
Isn't it like a festival? Wait, what about shaved ice?
ちょっと待って、待って！
Wait, wait, wait!
めっちゃしょげた。
She's so discouraged.
励まして、励まして！
Encourage her, encourage her!
夏だよね。ほら、夏だよね。
It's summer, you know? See, it's summer.
夏だよね！
It's summer!
夏だよね。ガサガサ、夏だよね。
It's summer. *rustle* It's summer.
夏だよね！ガサガサ、夏だよね！
It's summer! *rustle* It's summer!
でも答え変わって... あの、答え合ってねぇからな。
But the answers didn't... um, the answers didn't match.
いや、それ今変えただけだもんね。
Well, we just changed them now.
じゃ、不正解ということで。
So, it's incorrect.
なんだよ、違うのかよ。
What, it's not right?
もう、みんなトワの配信だからって暴れ散らかしてるでしょ！
Everyone's just going wild because it's Towa's stream, aren't they!
トワ様が暴れてんじゃねーのかよこれ！
Isn't Towa-sama the one going wild here!
そうだそうだ！
That's right, that's right!
お前が一番暴れてんだよ！
You're the one going wildest!
やめてー！
Stop it!
はい、じゃ、そしたら次、ドーン！
Okay, then, next one! Boom!
やばいよ、全然当たってないよ。
This is bad, we haven't gotten any right.
お題：海で遊びたいものを全員一致
Topic: Something you want to play at the sea - All in agreement
海で遊びたいものを、全員一致！
Something you want to play at the sea, all in agreement!
おー！遊びたい！
Oh! I want to play!
これはもう、あ、そうだぞ。食べ物で遊ぶな中出てくるぞ。
This is already... oh, right. Something about 'playing' besides food will come up.
あ、そうだね。そう、海で遊びたいもの。
Oh, that's true. Right, something to play at the sea.
一個決めて行こうか。決まった？みんな。
Let's decide on one. Decided, everyone?
決まったー！
Decided!
よし、海で遊びたいもの。行くよ。せーの！
Okay, something to play at the sea. Here we go. Ready...
これ！
This!
あー！
Ah!
あれ？
Wait?
え？
Eh?
水鉄砲じゃねーな。
It's not a water gun.
ペコちゃん、慰めて慰めて！
Peko-chan, comfort her, comfort her!
よしよし。
There, there.
夏だよね。ほら。
It's summer, you know? See.
夏だよねー！
It's summer!
夏だよね！
ガサガサ、夏だよねー！
*rustle* It's summer!
最後にするのやめて。最後に。最後にするの。語尾にするの。
Stop with the 'last word' thing! (the 'Natsu da yo ne' loop)
やばいって。ぼたんちゃんだけ、水鉄砲でした。
This is bad. Only Botan-chan had a water gun.
一人で遊んどこーわ。寂しすぎる。
I'll just play by myself. That's so sad.
寂しーい！
It's lonely!
悲しいよ、もう。
How tragic.
はい、ということで、なんと次で最終問題です！
Okay, so, somehow it's already time for the last question!
えー！
Eh?!
まじ？やばいじゃん、これ。
Seriously? This is bad.
全然揃ってないよ、これ。重大発表なし？これ。
We haven't matched at all. Is there no major announcement?
ここで終わっちゃうんじゃねーのかよ。
Isn't it going to end right here?
大丈夫、ここでっていうか、一個当たってるから、大丈夫じゃね？
It's okay, because we've gotten one right, so it's fine, right?
あ、そっか、そっか。
Oh, I see, I see.
じゃ、最後当てて、綺麗に。まあね。
Then let's get the last one right and finish cleanly. Right.
有終の美を飾りましょう。
Let's finish on a high note.
ということで、最後のお題はこちら！
So the last topic is this!
お題：常闇トワとかぶらないものを選べ！
Topic: Choose something that doesn't overlap with Tokoyami Towa!
常闇トワとかぶらないものを選べ！
Choose something that doesn't overlap with Tokoyami Towa!
えー！むずー！かぶっちゃダメか。
Eh! That's hard! We must not overlap?
いや、これトワだったら、これ一択やんね。
Well, if it's Towa, she'll definitely choose this one.
え、どういうこと？トワ様が大好きそうなやつとかぶんなくていいってこと？
Wait, what does that mean? Just that we shouldn't pick what Towa-sama likes?
そう、トワが。わかった、これ。これでいくわ。
Yeah, what Towa picks. Got it, this. I'll go with this.
あるもの選んでトワとかぶってもいいんだもんね。決まった？
We can pick something and it's okay if it overlaps with others as long as it's not Towa, right? Decided?
決まった。
Decided.
あ、ごめん、ちょっと待って。えっと、かぶらないものね。
Oh, sorry, wait a second. Um, something that doesn't overlap.
そうだよ。
That's right.
はい。
Yes.
よし。行くよ。まじ頼むよ、最後だよ。
Okay. Here we go. Please, it's the last one.
行くよ。せーの！
Ready... Go!
これ！
This!
おー！
Oh!
おおおー！当たった！
Ooooh! We got it!
やった！当たった！
Yay! We got it!
嬉しい！
So happy!
で、こちらは成功！
And this is a success!
イエーイ！やっぱ最後は決めんだよ。
Yay! We always nail the end.
そうそう。
Right, right.
凄ーい、最後は決めんだよ。
Amazing, we nailed the end.
凄ーい、分かったのみんな、凄ーい。
Amazing, how did everyone know? Amazing.
分かってないから。分かってないから成功したんだ。
I didn't know. That's why we succeeded.
そういうことか。
I see.
え、ということで、これまでの結果は...
Eh, so, the results so far are...
9問中...
Out of 9 questions...
3問成功！
3 questions correct!
凄ーい！
Amazing!
これ、いいんでしょう？どうですか？
Is this okay? How is it?
おっ。
Oh.
はっ。来た！謎猫。
Ha. Here she is! The mystery cat.
言ってなかったけど、
I didn't say it before, but...
全てのお題を成功させないと、僕の「魔力」は分けられないからねー。
if you don't succeed in all the topics, I can't share my 'magic' with you~
残念だったね。
That's too bad.
えー！無理ゲーだ！
What?! It's an impossible game!
みんなが頑張ってる姿は可愛かったよ。
Seeing you all work hard was cute though.
それじゃーね！
See ya!
お粥ー！
Okayu-ma!
なんなんだよー、これ！
What was that?!
待ってよー！
Wait up!
へー。
Oh?
いいじゃない。
That's good.
あの、箱壊してなんか魔力...
Um, like breaking boxes to get magical power...
やっちまおぺこ、もう！
Let's just do it already, peko!
じゃあ、やっちまお。
Then let's do it.
やっちゃお、やっちゃお、やっちゃおうかな。
Let's do it, let's do it! Maybe I'll do it!
とか思ったけど、なんかみんなと
I was thinking that, but after...
楽しく遊んでたら、すごいなんか魔力が体中からみなぎってきた気が...
...playing with everyone, I feel like magical power is surging through my body...
え、ちょっと待って。魔力って我々も感じることできる？
Wait a second. Can we feel magical power too?
や、でき...できるかも。
Well, maybe... you can.
嘘。
No way.
きめー！
Gross!
違う！
No!
え、何？
Eh, what?
あ、こぼれた！
Ah, it spilled!
何！？
What!?
漏れた！
It leaked!
だだ漏れって言いました？今。
Did you just say it's leaking all over?
何やねん。
What's with that?
ちょっと壊れちゃったみたい、トワ。
I think I broke a little, Towa.
重大発表ができる気がしてきた！
I feel like I can make the big announcement now!
トワ様の重大発表には、重大発表にふさわしいステージがあるぺこなんじゃないですか？
For your big announcement, shouldn't there be a stage worthy of it, peko?
あるのよ、あるのよ。
There is, there is.
いや、『あるのよ、あるのよ』って。新地の奥様かお前は。
What's with the "There is, there is"? Are you some high-class lady?
あるのよ、あるのよ。
There is, there is.
ちょっと準備してさ、行ってきますからね、皆さん。いいかしら？
I'll go prepare and then head there, everyone. Is that alright?
あ、ちょっと、あ、ちょっとマジで頑張りたいから落ち着いて行ってくるわ。
Wait, I really want to do my best, so I'll go calmly.
いってらっしゃーい！
Have a good one!
頑張れトワ様ー！
Good luck, Towa-sama!
みんなー！聞こえてるー？
Everyone! Can you hear me?
はい、改めまして、ホロライブ4期生の常闇トワ様です！
Yes, once again, I'm Hololive 4th gen's Tokoyami Towa-sama!
ゲストとの絆チェック、どうだったかな？
How was the bond check with the guests?
トワはね、楽しかったよ。
I had a lot of fun.
はい、そしてね、なんとゲストのみんなと楽しんだ後は、歌！
Yes, and then, after having fun with all the guests, comes the singing!
ライブパートで盛り上がりましょう！
Let's get pumped in the live part!
みんな、盛り上がる準備はできてるかー！？
Everyone, are you ready to get pumped!?
うおー！
Whoo!
って言ってくれてるだろう。
I bet you're saying that.
はい、ライブパート中には、
Yes, and during the live part,
超、超、超、超重大発表があるので最後までお見逃しなく！
there's a super, super big announcement, so don't miss it until the very end!
一体、どんな発表なのか...
Just what kind of announcement is it...
ドキドキが止まらない！
My heart won't stop throbbing!
ということで、みんなも楽しみだよね？
So, you guys are looking forward to it too, right?
はい。それでは、開演までもう少々お待ちください。
Yes. Well then, please wait a little longer until the show starts.
以上、常闇トワ様でした！
That's all from Tokoyami Towa-sama!
バイちゃ！
Bye-cha!
ライメイ
Raimei
だって私いつまでも ずっと虜 君以外はもう有り得ない
For I am forever captivated, there's no one else but you anymore
ちょっといつもフラフラ どっち向くの 思わせぶり許さないからね
You're always wandering, looking away, I won't forgive your suggestive behavior
好きだよって 強気になって 甘やかして もっと
Say you love me, be bold, and spoil me more
あのね 無理だよって 駆けるよって 触れたって 終わらせるから
Listen, even if you say it's impossible, even if I run or touch you, I'll end it
ガラスハート振り回して 骨の髄までしゃぶり尽くして
Swing around your glass heart, suck it dry to the marrow
壊れるほど惑わせて You know, you know, you know
Beguile me until I break, you know, you know, you know
ダビデの星を転がして 時空を駆け巡って
Roll the Star of David, travel through time and space
痺れる声は ライメイ
That numbing voice is Raimei
勝手な妄想なんだけど こっち向いて 君以外はもう愛せない
It's just a selfish delusion, but look this way, I can't love anyone but you anymore
きっと気分屋なんだけど いつか私 焼きもちで狂いそうだから
I'm sure you're moody, but I feel like I'll go crazy with jealousy someday
気づいちゃって 惹きつけたい ずっと
Notice me, I want to keep drawing you in forever
これは サンクコスト ただの愛情 なんでもいいけど
This is a sunk cost, just affection, call it whatever you like
自分勝手で手なずけて 盗み顔で抱きおこして
Tame me selfishly, pull me up with a sneaky face
あざといぐらいの笑顔で You know, you know, you know
With a smile that's almost too clever, you know, you know, you know
その悪魔で不敵なのに ヤバい軌跡の見事な仕草
Even though you're a fearless devil, those gestures follow a crazy trajectory
甘い 惑わすほどに 遠ざかる
Sweet, as it beguiles, it drifts away
気分次第でもっと頂戴 幻だって That's alright
Depending on the mood, give me more, even if it's an illusion, that's alright
このまま 地獄へ さあ Jump together
Just like this, to hell, let's jump together
Lon lon lon lon lon...
ガラスハート振り回して
Swing around your glass heart
歌った今までの全部
Everything I've sung so far
あなた自身の心だって
It's your own heart too
You know, you know, you know ダビデの星を転がして
You know, you know, you know, roll the Star of David
私だけを愛していて
Love only me
壊滅的なほど 痺れる声は
Devastatingly numbing, that voice is...
ライメイ
Raimei
ミッドナイト・ランナウェイ
Midnight Runaway
蒼い星に生まれて 違う道を歩いて
Born on a blue star, walking different paths
辿り着いた この街 光る粒が弾けた
I arrived in this city, where particles of light burst
巡るように君と出会い いつの間にか手を繋いで
We met as if destined, and before I knew it, we were holding hands
笑い声と弾む足で どこまでも駆け抜ける Midnight
With laughter and bouncing steps, we run anywhere through the midnight
見上げた空 星の光 街のネオンが混じり合って
The starlight in the sky above blends with the city's neon
憂鬱な日々を忘れて 悪戯な苦い経験も全部捨て去って
Forget the gloomy days, throw away all those mischievous, bitter experiences
僕らもっと自由なはず 閉ざした羽を開いたなら
We should be more free; if we open our closed wings
退屈な日々にさよなら 夜の街を行こう さあ
Goodbye to boring days, let's head into the night city, come on
ビルを抜けて 街を追い越して
Pass through the buildings, overtake the city
さよなら蒼い星 なんておどけて
Say "Goodbye, blue star" in jest
どこまで行こう 変わらないものなんて
Where shall we go? Since things that never change...
何もないから ただ一つだけ
Don't exist at all, just one thing...
...いけない今を偽善で
...present I cannot paint, with hypocrisy
踊る夜に君を連れて
I'll take you with me into the dancing night
邪魔なものは何にもなくて
There's nothing to get in our way
歌う声と軽い足で
With singing voices and light footsteps
いつまでも駆けるミッドナイト
Running through the midnight forever
見上げた空 月の光
The sky I looked up at, the moonlight
街の喧騒が光り合って
The bustle of the city shines together
憂鬱な日々を忘れて
Forgetting the melancholy days
いたずらな笑みに愛嬌とプライドを 全部捨て去って
Throwing away all the charm and pride from that mischievous smile
見上げた空 星の光
The sky I looked up at, the starlight
街のネオンが混じり合って
The city's neon lights blending together
退屈な日々にさよなら
Farewell to the boring days
僕の手を取って
Take my hand
さあ
Come on
常世の闇に囚われたまま
Trapped in the darkness of the eternal world
奏でる悲鳴を
The screams that play out
聞かせて
Let me hear them
FACT
作詞・作曲・編曲：niki
Lyrics, Composition, Arrangement: niki
さあ 爪を磨いたら
Come, once you've sharpened your claws
まだ子供のような貴方のために
For you, who are still like a child
ああ 試されたいなら
Ah, if you wish to be tested
その愚かな手に手錠をかけて
Place handcuffs on those foolish hands
常世の闇に囚われたまま
Trapped in the darkness of the eternal world
甘い甘いガムを噛んでた
I was chewing sweet, sweet gum
いくつもの後悔を
Numerous regrets
さあ 避けて
Come, avoid them
さりげない合図に隠れた
Hidden in a casual sign
答えはすぐに分からせてあげる
I'll let you know the answer soon
卑劣な嘘にまみれた
Smeared with despicable lies
拒んだままに受け止めてあげる
I'll accept you even as you refuse
ほら 悲鳴を
Look, let me hear
聞かせて
Your screams
さあ 指を鳴らしたら
Come, once I snap my fingers
この孤独のような私のために
For me, who is like this loneliness
ああ 喉が渇いたわ
Ah, my throat is parched
紅の下唇に指を忍ばせて
Stealing a finger to my crimson lower lip
狭い檻に閉じ込めたまま
Locked away in a narrow cage
首輪に繋がれたいんでしょ
You want to be tied to a collar, don't you?
くだらないルールじゃ奪えない
You can't take it away with worthless rules
自由はすでにこの手の中にある
Freedom is already in these hands
愛情では測れない
It cannot be measured by love
弱ったままに這わせてあげる
I'll let you crawl while you're weak
ほら 心を
Look, open
開いて
Your heart
分からないふりをして
Pretending not to understand
寝ぼけてるの？ もっと熱い
Are you half-asleep? Show me
暗闇を見せて
A more passionate darkness
ねえ
Hey
さりげない合図に隠れた
Hidden in a casual sign
答えはすぐに分からせてあげる
I'll let you know the answer soon
卑劣な嘘にまみれた
Smeared with despicable lies
拒んだままに受け止めてあげる
I'll accept you even as you refuse
常世の闇に刻むこの名を
Carve this name into the eternal darkness
分からせてあげる
I'll make you understand
ほら 悲鳴を 聞かせてよ
Look, let me hear your screams
夢見ないで
Don't dream
ほら聞かせて
Look, let me hear them
人間界に舞い降りた小悪魔
A little devil descended to the human world
様々な出会いが運命を変えていく
Various encounters changed fate
晴れの日も、雨の日も、信じる道を一歩ずつ歩み
On sunny days and rainy days, walking the path I believe in one step at a time
世界と繋がった、多様な想いが芽生え
Connected with the world, various feelings sprouted
今、開花する
Now, blooming
2023.9.27
1st アルバム 発売決定！
1st Album release decided!
ASTER
Tokoyami Towa 1st Album "Aster"
常闇トワ 1st Album ASTER
2023.9.27 Release
Tokoyami Towa 1st Album ASTER
生まれた 赤い花
The red flower that was born
ただこの国
Just in this country
ゆらゆら
Swaying
答えのないまま
Without an answer
運命はもろく 愚かな結末
Fate is a fragile and foolish ending
磔にされた心は泣いてる
The crucified heart is crying
手のひらから散る 悲し雫が
The sad drops scattering from the palm of my hand
あなたには見えていないのでしょう
You probably cannot see them
ならば ここまで
If so, this far
悲しい声に言葉に追いやられて
Driven away by sad voices and words
俯いたまま 微笑んだ赤い花
The red flower smiled while looking down
深く根を張る痛みが 贖罪なら
If the deep-rooted pain is atonement
分かり合えない ずっとこのまま
We can't understand each other, forever like this
変わらない定めに 心理は移ろい
In the unchanging fate, the truth shifts
むき出しにされて 掲げた不一致
Exposed and held up, the disagreement
有り触れた刃を 振りかざす
Wielding an ordinary blade
あなたには見えていないのでしょう
You probably cannot see it
もう 消えない傷
The wound that will no longer disappear
風が吹くように 散ってしまう花の色を
The color of the flower that scatters like the wind blows
あなたも知ることも きっとないでしょう
You probably won't ever know it either
どこまでも 落ちていく赤い景色
The red scenery falling endlessly
俯いたまま 泣いてた赤い花
The red flower was crying while looking down
朽ちていく心の中 まだ願ってる
Inside the decaying heart, still wishing
ありのまま 生きていたいと
That I want to live as I am
悲しい声に言葉に追いやられて
Driven away by sad voices and words
散り行く アネモネ
The scattering Anemone
深く根を張る痛みが 消えなくても
Even if the deep-rooted pain doesn't disappear
諍い続ける 何度だって
I'll continue to struggle, time and time again
淡い想いに 手を伸ばして
Reaching out my hand to the faint feelings
VTuberとしての私
Myself as a VTuber
周りからみた私
Myself as seen by others
ワタシがおもう私
The 'me' that I think of
固定概念
Fixed concepts
世間体
Social appearances
自己暗示から
From self-suggestion
もっと私らしくあるために
To be more like myself
私を縛る XXXを
The XXX that binds me
破壊せよ
Break
悲しい声に言葉に追い詰められて
Cornered by sad voices and words
うつむいたまま微笑む赤い花
A red flower smiling while looking down
深く根を張る痛みが
The pain that roots deeply
贖罪なら
If it's atonement
笑って癒えない
It cannot be healed with a laugh
ずっとこのまま
Staying like this forever
みんなー！
Everyone!
はい！
Yes!
なんと、常闇トワの1stアルバム発売と...
Unbelievably, Tokoyami Towa's 1st album release and...
...ソロライブの開催が決定しましたー！
...the solo live concert has been decided!
やばいね、やばい。もう本当に今日まですごい、もうドキドキしてました発表できる日。
It's crazy, crazy. I've been so nervous until today, the day I can announce it.
ここからはね、大事な情報ばっかりなので、えー、よく聞いてください。
From here on, it's all important information, so please listen carefully.
まずは、常闇トワ1stアルバム『ASTER』が、えー、2023年、
First, Tokoyami Towa's 1st album 'ASTER' will be released in 2023,
今年9月27日に発売されます！
on September 27th this year!
いや、すごい、あの、なんて言うの、神秘的なイラストだよね。
Wow, it's like, what do you call it, a mystical illustration, right?
はい、ちょっと素敵な美しいトワになっております。はい。
Yes, it's a bit of a wonderful, beautiful Towa. Yes.
ソロアルバムなんですけれども、みんなすごい「トワ様のソロアルバム欲しい」ってすごい言ってくれてたので、
It's a solo album, but everyone was saying 'I want Master Towa's solo album' so much,
本当に発表できて嬉しいです。
so I'm really happy to be able to announce it.
えー、このソロアルバムなんですけれども、すごいこだわって作ったので、作っているので、今。
Um, about this solo album, I've put a lot of care into making it, I'm making it right now.
ぜひお楽しみにしといてください。
Please look forward to it.
マジで、えー、本当にすごいよ。
Seriously, it's really amazing.
はい、そしてなんと、こちらのアルバムの販売店でアルバムを買ってくれた人には特典が付きます。
Yes, and surprisingly, those who buy the album at these stores will get bonuses.
特典はこちら。
Here are the bonuses.
はい、色んなね、お店があるんですけれども、お店ごとに色んなね特典があるので、
Yes, there are various shops, and each shop has different bonuses,
みんなチェックしてみてください。
so everyone please check them out.
あ、コメントありがとう。マジ見えてるよ。楽しみとか、スパチャも嬉しいし、
Oh, thanks for the comments. I can really see them. 'Looking forward to it', super chats too,
もう色んな人のコメントも嬉しいし。「ライブ！」とかね。
and comments from all sorts of people make me happy. Like 'Live!'.
見えてるよ、みんな。ありがとう。
I see you, everyone. Thank you.
みんなのおかげだよ、マジで。これガチだよ。ガチガチ。
It's thanks to everyone, seriously. I mean it. Really, really.
本当にありがとう。嬉しいよ、マジで。
Thank you so much. I'm really happy, seriously.
この後もね、配信したらしたら、もう触れるんですけれども。
I'll mention it again later during the stream, but...
はい、で、今日はね、その中からホロライブプロダクション公式オフィシャルショップの特典をお見せしちゃいます。
Yes, and today, I'll show you the bonus from the Hololive Production official shop.
こちら！ドーン！
This one! Boom!
どうですか？これやばくない？
How is it? Isn't this crazy?
えーと、なんと、こちら、えー、箔押しのね、こういう... 本当はねこういう感じじゃないんだけど、
Um, incredibly, this is a foil-stamped... well, it's not usually like this,
ホロライブでよくすると、こうCDのデザインがこういう形になっております。
but when it's done at Hololive, the CD design looks like this.
いや、マジで綺麗。
No, seriously, it's beautiful.
え、もう色んなとこでゲットするのもあり。あり。
And, getting it from various places is also an option. Definitely.
だって、いっぱいね、色んな種類が揃えられるから。ちゅうてね。
Because you can collect many different kinds. Just saying.
ということで特典をねチラ見せしたところで、
So now that I've given you a peek at the bonuses,
どんなアルバムになっているのか、少し紹介したいと思います。
I'd like to introduce a bit about what kind of album it is.
この『ASTER』ではトワのね、色んなね、そのデビューしてから今までとか、
In this 'ASTER', it's an album packed with various things like from my debut until now,
まぁ色んなこういうことがあって、こんなことがあって、こんな気持ちだよ、みたいな、
and how this and that happened, and these are my feelings, and so on.
色んなのを詰め込んだアルバムになってまして。
It's an album packed with all sorts of things.
曲がね、もう「こんな曲もあるのか」「こんな曲もあるのか」とか、なんかその結構ね、なんて言うの？
The songs, you'll be like 'There's a song like this too?' or 'And this one too?', it's quite... what do you call it?
似てない？似てないっていうの？その、全部がバラバラだから、
Varied? Is that the word? Since they're all different,
本当に「こんなトワ様もいるのか」とか、「これよ、これよのトワ」もいるので、
there's the 'Is there a Master Towa like this too?' and the 'This is it, this is the classic Towa' as well,
ぜひ楽しみにしててください。
so please look forward to it.
なんかカッコいい曲とかね、しっとりした曲とか、あと、そう！
Like cool songs, mellow songs, and also, yes!
トワがね、こうやって活動してきて、トワにしかできないこと。
Things only I can do after active for this long.
トワの、トワに似合ってる曲っていうのかな？なんて言うんだろう。
My songs, or songs that suit me? How should I put it?
トワの曲、あっと驚くような「あ、これはトワ様だ、わかるわかる」みたいな曲もあるので、お楽しみに！
My songs, there are also surprising songs where you'll go 'Ah, this is definitely Master Towa, I get it', so look forward to it!
はい、そして今日、あの先ほどね、サプライズで披露させていただいたのが
Yes, and the song I performed as a surprise just now
アルバムに収録される新曲『アネモネ』でした！
was the new song from the album, 'Anemone'!
『アネモネ』のジャケット写真を... こちら！ポン！こっち。
The jacket photo for 'Anemone' is... this! Pop! This side.
はい、このアルバムのリード曲になっておりまして、めちゃくちゃね、
Yes, it's the lead track of this album, and the composer, Yurii Canon-san,
その「こんな気持ちで活動してます」とか「こんな思いもありました」とかっていうのを...
really captured things like 'I'm active with these feelings' and 'I had these thoughts too'.
相談してあの
I talked it over and,
トワ様っぽく仕上げましたって言って
they said, "We've made it look just like Towa-sama,"
作られた曲なので
and that's how this song was created.
もう歌詞とか
The lyrics and also,
あとMVもねこの後9時から
the music video will be released at 9 PM today,
公開するんですけれども
we're going to make it public,
トワのチャンネルで
on Towa's channel.
公開するんですけれども
It'll be released there.
気合いもね入ってて
A lot of effort went into it,
素敵なMVとなっておりますので
it's a wonderful music video, so,
ぜひ
please,
よろしくお願いします
look forward to it!
そして24時からね 各種配信サイトで
And from midnight, it'll be on various streaming platforms,
聞くことができるので
so you can listen to it there.
えー寝る間も惜しんでえー寝ないでください
So, don't waste time sleeping, please don't sleep!
寝ないで全部聞いてください
Don't sleep and listen to it all.
ずっと一生ねとかいって
Listen to it forever. (Laughs)
あははとか言って
Ahahaha, I'm just kidding.
やばこれねあのね意外と静かなのよトワは
Wow, this is... well, Towa is actually surprisingly quiet.
えっとはい
Anyway, yes.
じゃあ寝ないで聞いてください
So, listen to it without sleeping.
はい恥ずかしい
Yes, I'm embarrassed.
えーそしてそして
And, and,
えー重大発表はアルバムだけではございません
the major announcement isn't just about the album!
常闇トワソロライブ
Tokoyami Towa solo live concert,
開催決定！
has been officially decided!
いえーいもうトワねえ
Yay! You know, Towa was like,
みんな「トワ様ソロライブいつなの？」
everyone kept asking, "When is Towa-sama's solo live?"
トワもやりたいんだよー
And I was like, "I want to do one too!"
「トワ様ソロライブ行きたいよ」
"I want to go to Towa-sama's solo live!"
トワもやりたいんだよー
And I wanted to do one so badly!
そんなことを何回も繰り返しておりました
We've said that so many times.
来ましたよみんな
It's finally here, everyone!
みんなマジで来た
It's really here!
えー常闇トワ1stソロライブ
Tokoyami Towa's 1st solo live,
Break your xxxが
'Break your xxx' will be on
2023年10月13日
October 13th, 2023,
立川ステージガーデンで開催されます
at Tachikawa Stage Garden!
えーこれねXじゃなくてバツなんです
And this, it's not 'X', it's 'cross' (batsu).
え、このバツに何が入るかは
As for what goes in place of this 'cross',
みんなの方で考えてください
I want all of you to decide.
壊したいもの 越えたいもの
Things you want to break, or things you want to surpass,
自分の殻を破りたいとか
like breaking out of your shell,
山を越えたいとか
or wanting to overcome mountains,
この壁をぶち壊して頑張りたいみたいな
breaking down walls and giving it your all.
そういう時にそういう感じでね
With that kind of feeling,
自分の様々なものを壊すっていう意味になってますので
it carries the meaning of breaking various things of yours.
えー自分のね考えてるもの当てはめてくれたら嬉しいなと思います
I hope you can fill it with whatever you're thinking of.
えーそしてアルバム Aster を
And with the album 'Aster'
メインとしてねこのソロライブをやります
as the main focus, we'll be doing this solo live.
そしてこのねソロライブなんですけれども
And regarding this solo live,
生バンド すべて生バンドでやらせていただきます
a live band! We'll be doing the entire show with a live band!
えーライブもアルバムも
The live and the album,
アルバムも 活舌がね アルバムも
the album also... my tongue is tripping... the album also,
ハッシュタグは #常闇トワ1stソロライブ で
please use the hashtag #TokoyamiTowa1stSoloLive
呟いてください
and tweet about it!
分かりやすいと思います よろしくお願いします
I think it's easy to understand. Thank you!
みんなありがとう
Thank you everyone!
えバツバツバツはリアルだと思う
Oh, "Cross-cross-cross" is real, I think.
キスだと思う ちょっとキスではないよ流スタにね
You think it's 'kiss'? It's definitely not 'kiss', obviously.
え、現地会場のチケットはこの後9時から
As for the venue tickets, from 9 PM today,
ホロライブファンクラブ公式のえー先行がスタートします
the Hololive Fan Club official advance lottery will start.
1階はスタンディング席
The 1st floor has standing areas,
2階3階がえー指定席となっておりまして
and the 2nd and 3rd floors have reserved seating,
それが発売されます
and those will be on sale.
受付期間は8月6日までで抽選形式なので
The application period is until August 6th, and it's a lottery,
焦らず申し込んでください
so please apply without rushing.
また現地には来れないよという人のために
Also, for those who can't come to the venue,
有料配信もあります
there will be a paid stream.
プラットフォームは Z-aN でこちらもチケット9時から販売開始です
The platform is Z-aN, and tickets for that also start at 9 PM.
ライブ終了後 11月13日までアーカイブが見放題
After the live ends, you can watch the archive until November 13th.
申し込みは概要欄のホームページや
To apply, please check the homepage in the description box,
ホロライブプロダクションのTwitterをチェックしてみてください
or Hololive Production's Twitter.
マネちゃんが更新してくれるんじゃないかなと思います
I think the manager will keep us updated.
はい そして次はお待ちかねの
Yes! And next is the long-awaited...
ライブといえばグッズが必要でしょう？
you can't have a live without merchandise, right?
はいどうぞ
Here you go!
ライブのグッズ紹介になります はい
This is the live merchandise introduction. Yes!
ライブのね定番アイテムがセットで登場
The live concert's standard items are appearing as a set.
この応援セットを購入すると特典でリストバンドがついてきます
If you buy this Support Set, it comes with a bonus wristband.
すごい可愛かったよ
It was really cute!
リストバンドでタオルを束ねて使ってみてください
Try using the wristband to bundle up your towel.
右下にあります
It's on the bottom right.
応援セットのグッズはね個別でも買うことができますので
You can also buy the items in the Support Set individually,
よろしくお願いします
so please check them out.
えーでは次
Now, the next ones,
バラバラのかな？
are the separate items.
えっとTシャツとペンライトとマフラータオルで
The T-shirt, penlight, and muffler towel.
ちょっとねカッコよめなものにしてみました
We've made them a bit on the cooler side.
えーこれはねライブをね応援する必須アイテムなんじゃないかなと思うので
I think these are essential items for supporting the live,
ぜひチェックお願いします
so please check them out.
でここからはあの ここまでが先行先行
Now, from here on... up to this point are the advance order goods.
ごめんごめんここまでが先行発送グッズなので
Sorry, sorry, up to this point are the advance shipping goods,
気をつけてくださいね
so please keep that in mind.
はい そして次は受注販売するグッズです
Yes! And next are the made-to-order goods.
これから紹介するアイテムはライブ後のお届けになるので注意してください
Please note that the items I'm about to show will be delivered after the live.
言いましたよ
I've said it now!
はい ロゴキーホルダーとキーケースとトートバッグです
Okay, the logo keychain, key case, and tote bag.
ロゴキーホルダーはね そう今回のキービジュアルのイラストが入ってる
The logo keychain has the key visual illustration,
あのものになっておりまして
featured on it.
キーケースはね ちょっとカッコよめなレザー風仕様のものになっております
The key case is a cool-looking, leather-style one.
トートバッグはね 結構普段使いしやすいんじゃないかなと思います
As for the tote bag, I think it's quite easy to use daily.
ライブの記念にぜひゲットしてみてください
Please get them as a memento of the live concert.
そしてまだまだ 次こちら
And there's more! Next is this.
缶バッジとステッカー アクリルスタンド タペストリーとなっております
The button badges and stickers, acrylic stand, and tapestry.
えっとねトワのねデビューしてからずっと描いてくださっている
Well, rurudo-sensei, who's been drawing me since my debut,
rurudo先生があの素敵なイラスト描いてくれましたので
has drawn some wonderful illustrations for these.
こちらのイラストを使ったグッズとなっておりますので
These goods use those illustrations, so,
あの ぜひゲットしてくれたら嬉しいなと思います
I'd be happy if you could get them.
はいということで
Okay, with that,
常闇トワ 1stアルバム 発売決定!
Tokoyami Towa 1st Album Release Decided!
Break your xxx
Tokoyami Towa 1st solo Live
2023.10.13 TACHIKAWA STAGE GARDEN
Tickets
現地会場チケット
1F スタンディング ¥8,800(税込)
2-3F 指定席 ¥8,800(税込)
配信チケット Z-aN ¥6,500(税込)
Tickets
Venue Tickets
1F Standing ¥8,800 (tax incl.)
2-3F Reserved Seats ¥8,800 (tax incl.)
Streaming Ticket Z-aN ¥6,500 (tax incl.)
記念にね、マジで買ってくださいっていう感じです。
Please buy them as a memento, seriously.
アクリルスタンドめっちゃ良いよ、トワ見たけど、
The acrylic stand is really good. I've seen it,
すごい良いからぜひよろしくお願いします。
and it's great, so please check it out.
ということで、最後にね、
So, finally,
購入時の注意事項をお伝えします。
I'll tell you the precautions for purchasing.
発売期間はこのあと9時から8月14日の6時までです。
The sales period is from 9 PM today until 6 PM on August 14th.
先行発送グッズと受注販売グッズと、先ほど紹介した
Early-shipment goods, made-to-order goods, and the previously introduced
ファーストアルバム「Aster」のお届けタイミングは全部違います。
first album 'Aster' all have different delivery timings.
また、ライブ先行発送の商品は、発送商品以外の商品と
Also, if you buy live early-shipment items
同じカート内で購入しちゃうと、発送期間内での発送ができません。
in the same cart as other items, they can't be shipped early.
みんなこれマジで注意ね。固めてね、同じもので。
Everyone, really be careful about this. Group the same types together.
例えばこのライブの受注グッズ、アルバム「Aster」、
For example, if you put this live's made-to-order goods, the album 'Aster',
そしてこのライブのグッズ以外のグッズを一緒に入れちゃうと、
and other non-live goods together in the same cart,
ライブに間に合わなくなっちゃいますと。
they won't arrive in time for the live.
まとめると、先行発送をご希望の場合は、
To summarize, if you want early shipment,
先行発送のグッズだけでのお買い上げをお願いしますということです。
please buy only early-shipment goods in one order.
マジでいつものやつ。でももうこれ言ったからね。
It's the usual thing. But I've said it now.
販売サイトの注意事項、よく確認してください。
Please check the precautions on the sales site carefully.
もう、あの、今言ったから。トワは責任を負いませーん。
I've said it now. Towa takes no responsibility!
はい。また一部グッズは在庫限りの販売となってますので、
Also, some items are limited in stock,
詳しくは各販売サイトと公演特設サイトをご確認ください。
so please check the sales sites and the concert site for details.
どのライブグッズもトワがほとんど全部決めたんですけど、
I decided on almost all of the live goods myself,
素敵にやってくださったので、ぜひみんなに手に取ってほしいなと思います。
and they turned out great, so I hope everyone gets them.
はい、ということで、すごい駆け足になってしまったんですけど、
So, it's been a bit of a rush, but
本当に今日このみんなに発表する日、
today, the day I announced this to you all,
そしてライブ当日もね、絶対またドキドキしてると思うんですけど...
and on the day of the live, I'm sure I'll be nervous again...
このドキドキを、当日までに、もっともっと頑張って、良いものにして、
I'll work hard until that day to make it even better,
このドキドキを強さに変えれるように頑張っていきますので、よろしくお願いします。
and turn this nervousness into strength. I'll do my best.
はい、ということで、今日はみんな、本当にありがとう！
Alright, thank you so much everyone for today!
アルバムもライブも楽しみにしていてください。
Please look forward to both the album and the live.
ではみんな9時からいっぱい情報が更新されるよう、よろしくね。
Lots of info will be updated from 9 PM, so check it out.
ということで、みんな、バイバーイ！マジでありがとう！
So, bye-bye everyone! Thank you so much!
バイバイ、バイバイ、バイバーイ！
Bye-bye, bye-bye, bye-bye!
VTuberとしての私
Me as a VTuber
周りからみた私
Me as seen by others
ワタシがおもう私
The me I think I am
XXX
固定概念
Stereotypes
世間体
Social reputation
自己暗示から
From self-hypnosis
もっと自由に
More freely
もっと私らしくあるために
To be more like myself
私を縛る、XXXを
The XXX that binds me
破壊せよ
Destroy it
悲しい声に 言葉に追いやられて
Driven away by sad voices and words
TOKOYAMI TOWA 1st SOLO LIVE
うつむいたまま 微笑む紅い花
A red flower smiling while looking down
2023.10.13 TACHIKAWA STAGE GARDEN
深く根を張る 痛みが贖罪なら
If the deep-rooted pain is atonement
分かち合えない ずっとこのまま
We can't share it, it'll stay this way forever